# Jennifer Ruel

Email: jenrueler@gmail.com Mobile: (414) 335-8283 LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/jenniferruel

City: Milwaukee, WI

I am an innovative person seeking a position as a software programmer. I have spent the last 10 years working as a high school Spanish teacher, and inventing new ways to teach urban youth the Spanish language, and I look forward to switching careers and spending many years solving problems in the technical world.

#### **Technical Skills**

ASP.NET, Javascript, C#, HTML 5, jQuery, Git, AJAX, Responsive Design, Agile, Microsoft Office, English, Spanish, Smartboard Technologies

### **Professional Experience**

Spanish Teacher - Riverside University High School August 2007 – November 2016

 Responsible for planning, teaching, and maintaining discipline in classes, collaborating with colleagues to improve lessons, meeting with parents and administration to present and improve student participation and performance

Cycling Instructor - Riverside University High School October 2007 – May 2015

Responsible for teaching bicycling safety and riding skills to youth, providing first aid and bicycle
maintenance on the road as necessary, reporting any injuries or problems

Spanish Teacher - Franklin High School

June 2016 - August 2016

Graduated: February 2017

 Responsible for planning, teaching, and maintaining discipline in summer Spanish classes for middle school age students

## **Projects**

Sound Mind - https://github.com/jenrules/SoundMind

Sound Mind is an ASP.NET application that I designed to help people that live with a mental illness to better manage their recovery. The user has access to soothing music, a paint bucket activity, a medication reminder, a quote of the day, relaxation activities, and the ability to send an emergency text.

#### **Education**

devCodeCamp Milwaukee, WI

Over 600 hours of coding experience focused on HTML 5, C#, Javascript, and ASP.NET

University of Wisconsin – Milwaukee Graduated: December 2006

Bachelor of Science in Education